Sepideh Chitsaz

Rockville, MD 20851

Phone: (240) 918-8675 | E-mail: sepideh.chitsaz@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sepideh-chitsaz/ | Portfolio: https://sepidehchitsaz.com/

UX Researcher | UI Designer | Web Developer

UX/UI designer with a background in linguistics and behavior therapy. Persistent, problem solver, and passionate to help people. Strong skills in conducting quantitative and qualitative research, knowledge in human behavior, and fine arts background to enhance knowledge as a designer. Earned a certificate in UX/UI from George Washington University.

Technical Skills

Technical: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap

UX/UI: User-Centric Design Research, Visual Prototyping & Wireframing, User Interface Development

Projects

TaskMaster | https://bit.ly/3b3a0DR

- Summary: TaskMaster was designed to assist individuals with autism who struggle with daily hygiene tasks. Many of these users do enjoy playing on an electronic device. Therefore, by implementing an application, their attention might be gained and being motivated to do these tasks on their own.
- Role: UX/UI designer and Autism Therapy Consultant
- Skills Used: User Experience Design (UI/UX), User Research Interview, Information Architecture, Interaction Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Making the design responsive for Mobile & Web, Usability Testing.

Save The Frogs | https://bit.ly/33muhjy

- Summary: The goal of this project was to redesign the website based on the usability testing results to bring in more awareness, volunteer interest, and donations for the betterment of amphibian conservation efforts.
- Role: UX/UI designer.
- Skills Used: User Experience Design (UI/UX), User Research (Survey & Interview), Information Architecture, Interaction Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Making the design responsive for Mobile & Web, Usability Testing.

Click | https://bit.ly/3vRDD3

- Summary: Click is a knowledge-sharing app for photographers of all levels. Through Click, photographers will be
 able to find photography locations for their next shoot as well as suggest and review locations themselves while
 sharing their photos.
- Role: UX researcher and designer.
- Skills Used: User Research (Interviews & Surveys) & Analysis, Mobile User Experience Design (UX-UI), Interaction Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, User Testing

US Department of Education | https://bit.ly/3emeUOA

- Summary: Based on the users' struggles to find information and the outdated look of the US Department of Education website, the goal of this project was to redesign the website to make it user friendly.
- Role: UX researcher and designer.
- Skills Used: User Experience Design (UI/UX), User Research Interview, Information Architecture, Interaction Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Making the design responsive for Mobile & Web, Usability Testing.

Experiences

Vista Eye Center, Rockville, MD, USA, October 2020 – Present

Receptionist/Medical Assistant

- Check-in patients, enter data in the system, communicate with the insurances, balance the books, buy office items, etc.
- Assist the doctor in vision measurement and working with imaging tools.
- Recognized by the provider 25% increase of the number of patients with less cancelations per day. Provided organized documents (paper/digital) which are easy to access for the staff.

Department of Medicine and Cancer Center, Howard University, March 2018 - Present

Research Assistant

- Conducted Literature Review on topics related to Autism.
- Proposed research projects.

Center for Autism and Related Disorders (CARD), Rockville, MD, USA, May 2018 - October 2020

Behavior Technician

- Completed Applied Behavior Analysis (ABA) with individuals with Autism age range 3-22 years old in person and online.
- Provided the clients with different skills to become more independent.
- Progress in doing tasks with significant less number of tantrums were observed by the supervisor and parents.

Research Assistant

- Conducted Literature Review/Data Collection.
- Collaborated in several projects.

Maedeh NGO, September 2013 – January 2018

Event Organizer/Instructor (Volunteering)

- Organized lifestyle skill programs and outdoor activities to the parents of children with special needs.
- Taught courses to help parents of children with special needs to navigate their special needs related challenges.
- Provided parents with activities to cope with the challenges and problems to better their lives.

University of Malaya (Faculty of Languages and Linguistics), Malaysia, September 2011- July 2013.

Graduate Research Assistant

- Conducted literature review, data collection, and data analysis in several projects.
- Organized several meetings, seminars, and conferences at the university.

Education

Certificate in UX/UI Designer, The George Washington University (GW), USA, 2021.

Ph.D. in Clinical Linguistics, School of Rehabilitation Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University Kebangsaan Malaysia (UKM), Malaysia, 2007-2013.

Master of Arts in Linguistics, Department of Linguistics and Foreign Languages, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran, 2004.

Bachelor of Arts in English Language Translation, Azad University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran, 1997.

Certificates

Qualitative Research Methods: Conversational Interviewing, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), 2020.

Registered Behavior Technician (RBT), 2019.